PERSONAL SUMMARY

Dhirendra is an Analytics Manager focussed on building data products and solutions driven by machine learning algorithms to make business ideas actionable. Roles played as Data Scientist, Business Consultant, Visualisation Expert, DWBI Professional, Developer, has culminated into him being a General Manager today. In doing so, it has honed him into a skilled collaborator comfortable working across key business areas to deploy analytical insights. Good planning skills have come in handy in leading multiple projects of varying scales simultaneously.

HIGHLIGHTS

New Product DevelopmentProblem SolvingQuick LearnerPresentationData VisualizationAttention to DetailBusiness Process AnalysisBusiness IntelligenceMachine Learning

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE (9 years)

Technosoft Corporation

Role: Product Manager - SensER (Company IP – Analytics)

February 2015 - Present

- Product owner of Advanced Analytics enriched BI solution for Emergency Room (ER) provider market
- Unique feature roadmap: Included embedded Analytics in collaboration with a US based ER provider group
- Product Positioning: Enabled sales to take the solution to market through conferences and prospective client demonstrations, Brochures, Trainings, Pricing strategy, Presentations
- Stakeholder Management: Working with US based client, billing team, Marketing and Sales team
- Solution Development: Designed and managed development of supporting applications such as *Call-back*, *Deficiency-tracking* programs

Role: Product Manager - Solution for Detection of Stress in Emergency Room providers

- Led the development of solution which includes development of: Android App to capture data; Algorithm to detect Psychological stress using Physiological data collected through the *Empatica* E4 device
- Deployed the solution for data collection on field in six hospitals in the US for a period of three weeks

Role: Advanced Analytics Consultant

- Anomaly Detection: Identification of Anomalous Providers based on selected parameters over a period of time using different approaches including *Large-scale unusual time series detection*, *Clustering*
- Payment Reconciliation: Using *integer programming* to reconcile bank statements with records from the billing management system for a billing provider
- Ambulance Auto-coding:
 - Automatic generation of HCPCS code from ambulance trip notes using Natural Language Processing
 - o Packaging for secure delivery over cloud to process up to over 1000 trip notes per second
- Retirement Planning: Evaluate feasibility of having a desired annual retirement income for a span of 'N' years using *Monte Carlo Simulation*
- Collection Forecasting: Predicting collections from Insurance using Regression techniques such as ARIMA
- Team building: Capability building, planning, facilitating and conducting sessions on Data Science, and Healthcare Revenue Cycle Management

Role: Data Visualization Expert

- · Visualization advice to UI/UX projects, BI projects for internal developments and client engagements
- Conceptualising and building capability (Spotfire), training, non-conventional use case adoption

Hewlett Packard

June 2011 - January 2015

Role: Program Manager

- Provide Marketing expertise to business for Data Centre and Platform Consulting services with focus on SMAC
- Develop value proposition and rich mix of marketing communication content and deliverables

Role: Product Manager - HP VideoBook (Wall Street Journal Award winning Analytics solution)

- Developing and executing a Go-to-market plan while working with senior management
- Defining market requirements from primary research for the product supported by on-going visits to customers, partners and focus group study
- Working with internal team and 3rd party developers to design the product and features based on user feedback for Android tablets and web-browsers

- Working closely with in-house teams (legal, marketing, branding, operations) to make the product ready and HP-compliant for market Product Sales and Marketing
- Field trial of the solution across schools and Launching the product to internal customers at HP, showcasing it at external events, customer locations, summits
- Working closely with global branding team and marketing agency to develop the product positioning, messaging and resulting collaterals, AVs

Role: Analytics Consultant - Social Intelligence

- Customer: Major Consumer Packaged Goods Company in India
 - Analysed analytics and social media landscape of the company to identify the gaps in the area of Sales
 Marketing with context to Information Management
- Customer: Major Two Wheeler Manufacturer in India
 - o Led a team to measure marketing effectiveness using data from social media conversations
 - o Provided direction to help extract qualitative insights on awareness, consideration, preference and purchase intent to the customer
- Customer: Major Two Wheeler Manufacturer in India
 - o Developed a custom analytics solution for customer clustering based on consumer demographics data
 - o Conducted two-day CXO level workshop to understand the current IT landscape
 - Consulted with top vendors in the GIS space to find the best fit to use GIS based maps as the layer for presentation of insights from the analytics offering

Citrus Hotels and Resorts

May 2010 - June 2010

Business Consultant

- Worked with Senior Management in laying the foundations for a digital presence and developed an exhaustive strategy for Digital and Social Media Marketing for the chain Hotels and Resorts
- Selected the marketing/media agency to implement the marketing strategy and guided its implementation

Infosys Technologies Limited

June 2006 - June 2009

Business Analyst and Technology Lead, DW/BI Solution Architect, MicroStrategy Developer Customers: Starbucks Coffee Company, Nordstorm Inc.

- Implementation of customer loyalty programs resulting in increased revenues
- Optimization of inventory across stores in US, Canada region by enhancing visibility in the supply chain
- End-to-end application development for employee performance reporting
- Mapped complex business processes to technical requirements

EDUCATION AND LEARNING

Indian Institute of Management (IIM), Kozhikode

2009 - 2011

Post Graduate Program in Management, Marketing and Operations

National Institute of Technology (NIT), Warangal

2002-2006

Bachelor of Technology, Chemical Engineering, First Class with Distinction

Independent Learning

- Machine Learning by Andrew Ng, Coursera
- Data Science and Machine Learning Essentials (Azure), edX
- Certified *MicroStrategy* Project Designer
- Others: English Composition by *Dr. Denise Comer*, Social Psychology by *Scott Plous*

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Employee of the Quarter Award for two Quarters, Technosoft
- Mentioned in two out of three CEO Quarterly Newsletters for contribution to SensER and Innovation
- Co-authored and presented a paper on innovation at the prestigious HP technology event, Tech Con '14, Florida. The abstract was among the 130 selected for final presentation out of 2000+ submissions
- Received HP e-award for exemplary contribution to *VideoBook* and innovation in Social Intelligence
- Interned in application of Kinetic Monte Carlo methods with Chemical Engineering Department, IIT Guwahati
- Long distance runner: Completed the gruelling Kaveri Trail Marathon barefoot in four hours 45 minutes